<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  
  <title><![CDATA[Matt Atkinson]]></title>
  <subtitle><![CDATA[A developers blog]]></subtitle>
  <link href="/atom.xml" rel="self"/>
  <link href="http://mattpker.com//"/>
  <updated>2015-07-14T21:26:06.000Z</updated>
  <id>http://mattpker.com//</id>
  
  <author>
    <name><![CDATA[Matt Atkinson]]></name>
    
  </author>
  
  <generator uri="http://hexo.io/">Hexo</generator>
  
  <entry>
    <title><![CDATA[My Editor: Atom]]></title>
    <link href="http://mattpker.com/2015/07/06/My-Editor-Atom/"/>
    <id>http://mattpker.com/2015/07/06/My-Editor-Atom/</id>
    <published>2015-07-06T18:04:10.000Z</published>
    <updated>2015-07-14T21:26:06.000Z</updated>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<center><img src="/images/atom.png" style="border:0px"></center>

<p>Coming from a background in Linux server administration, of course my first editor was Vim. I really like Vim as a basic editor, but when I started programing it really did not fit my needs. I realize that you can highly customize Vim and make it much like “modern” editors of today, this just seemed way to complex for me and I wanted something a bit more user friendly with mouse support.</p>
<p>The editor everyone recommended to me was <a href="http://www.sublimetext.com/" target="_blank" rel="external">Sublime 2</a>. I enjoyed the look and feel of Sublime, but it still did not seem as user friendly that I hoped. Even so, I decided to go ahead with it as it seemed to be the best option at that time.</p>
<p>I used Sublime 2 as my primary editor for about 2 years. I had it very customized to my liking and I was very confortable with it. So changing editors at this point was not even on my radar.</p>
<p>About 6 months ago I stumbled across <a href="https://atom.io/" target="_blank" rel="external">Atom</a>, an editor still in beta from GitHub. It was promising an awesome packaging system, theme support, GitHub support baked in, and powered all by NodeJS and web technologies. At the time I was really getting into NodeJS and decided that I wanted to give it a try to see what it was capable of.</p>
<p><img src="/images/atom2.png" alt="Atom Screenshot" title="Atom Screenshot"></p>
<p>Right out of the box Atom blew me away with an amazing packaging system. Within minutes I found a theme and syntax that I liked and all the comparable plugins I was using in Sublime 2. I felt at home with Atom as it was much like Sublime 2 and most the keyboard shortcuts were the same. It wasn’t till I started coding in an actual Git project that I realized I would not be going back to Sublime 2. It had built in Git support that I had never seen before, such as lines were colored that had been changed/added/deleted and the same thing with new/changed files/folders in the tree view.</p>
<p>Atom recently released <a href="http://blog.atom.io/2015/06/25/atom-1-0.html" target="_blank" rel="external">version 1.0</a> and at this point I would recommend it to everyone. It is extremely stable and they have greatly improved the startup time and speed. I am excited to see what they do next with Atom, hopefully some more great baked in GitHub features and solving the problem of opening very large files (200MB+).</p>
<h2 id="Recommended_Plugins">Recommended Plugins</h2><ul>
<li><a href="https://atom.io/packages/atom-beautify" target="_blank" rel="external">atom-beautify</a></li>
<li><a href="https://atom.io/packages/color-picker" target="_blank" rel="external">color-picker</a></li>
<li><a href="https://atom.io/packages/pigments" target="_blank" rel="external">pigments</a></li>
<li><a href="https://atom.io/packages/file-icons" target="_blank" rel="external">file-icons</a></li>
<li><a href="https://atom.io/packages/linter" target="_blank" rel="external">linter</a> - List of compatible linters <a href="http://atomlinter.github.io/" target="_blank" rel="external">http://atomlinter.github.io/</a></li>
<li><a href="https://atom.io/packages/merge-conflicts" target="_blank" rel="external">merge-conflicts</a></li>
</ul>
<h2 id="Recommended_Theme">Recommended Theme</h2><ul>
<li><a href="https://atom.io/themes/isotope-ui" target="_blank" rel="external">Isotope UI</a></li>
<li><a href="https://atom.io/themes/monokai" target="_blank" rel="external">Monokai Syntax</a></li>
</ul>
]]></content>
    <summary type="html">
    <![CDATA[<center><img src="/images/atom.png" style="border:0px"></center>

<p>Coming from a background in Linux server administration, of course my f]]>
    </summary>
    
      <category term="atom" scheme="http://mattpker.com/tags/atom/"/>
    
      <category term="editors" scheme="http://mattpker.com/tags/editors/"/>
    
      <category term="reviews" scheme="http://mattpker.com/tags/reviews/"/>
    
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title><![CDATA[My Blog]]></title>
    <link href="http://mattpker.com/2015/07/06/My-Blog/"/>
    <id>http://mattpker.com/2015/07/06/My-Blog/</id>
    <published>2015-07-06T17:17:13.000Z</published>
    <updated>2015-07-06T23:06:09.000Z</updated>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>I am starting a blog based on what I am currently doing in development and technology. I plan on having a new post at least every week. Head on over to the <a href="/about">about</a> page for more information about me.</p>
<p>This blog is being created with <a href="https://hexo.io/" target="_blank" rel="external">Hexo</a> and hosting on <a href="https://pages.github.com/" target="_blank" rel="external">GitHub Pages</a>. I wanted to use a blogging framework that used the same technologies that I am currently working with. When I get more well versed in Hexo, ill make a post reviewing it and even possibly a tutorial.</p>
<p>I am welcome to any feedback, hit me up on my twitter <a href="https://twitter.com/mattpker" target="_blank" rel="external">@mattpker</a> or use the commenting system.</p>
]]></content>
    <summary type="html">
    <![CDATA[<p>I am starting a blog based on what I am currently doing in development and technology. I plan on having a new post at least every week. H]]>
    </summary>
    
      <category term="hexo" scheme="http://mattpker.com/tags/hexo/"/>
    
  </entry>
  
</feed>